# Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, and sharing economy applications, can support newcomers, such as immigrants, dominant migrants, or travelers, in accessing resources in their new environments.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI, USA **Doctoral Candidate in Information** 09/2015 – present

Doctoral Candidate in Information Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University

M.S. in Computer Science

Taipei, Taiwan

09/2010 - 06/2013

M.S. in Computer Science
Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Moffett Field, CA, USA

Visiting Scholar
Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker

National Taiwan University

B.S. in Computer Science

Taipei, Taiwan
09/2006 - 06/2010

#### SELECTED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI, USA

#### Graduate Student Research Assistant

09/2015 – present g technologies to help low-

Support research of the Social Innovations Group, which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and educational resources (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

# Affiliated Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a social media user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Articles

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*, Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%; Presenter).

# Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In *Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18)*, Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In *Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17)*, 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In *Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13)*, 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).

• Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In *Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13*), 5150-5160.

## Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2019) Fostering Immigrants' Trust in Online Local Social Exchange. To be presented at The 22nd ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '19) Doctoral Consortium (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17)*, 1700 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15)*, 1893-1898 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

# SELECTED PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

### Academic Events & Activities

ACM MobileHCI 2019

09/2017 - Present

Student Volunteer Chair

Tai-CHI 2015 (The Annual Taiwanese Conference on Computer-Human Interaction) 01/2015 – 07/2015 Organizing Committee

OpenHCI Workshop 2013 (Student-Organized Workshop on HCI in Taiwan) 01/2013 - 07/2013

**Program Chair** 

Social Events & Activities

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

08/2018 - Present

Doctoral Committee - Student Representative

Annual Taiwan Night at CHI

2015 - 2018

Organizing Committee

#### Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017 - 2019; ACM CSCW 2017, 2018; ACM MobileHCI 2018; ACM TEI 2017;

#### Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2018, 2019; ACM COMPASS 2018; ACM CHI 2017;

## SELECTED TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Winter 2018

SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Fall 2017

SI-501: Contextual Inquiry Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama

# **SKILLS**

#### Research & Analysis Methods

Qualitative Methods

Semi-structured interview, diary study, qualitative coding

Quantitative Methods

Survey design, lab/field experiment, statistical analysis

#### Tool

Programming Language

Python, Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Analysis Tool R, NVivo

# Language

Mandarin Chinese (Native); English (Full professional proficiency); Japanese (Limited working proficiency)